Joshua deLorimier

302-494-3242 <u>JoshuadeLorimier@gmail.com</u> Philadelphia, PA

Github: https://github.com/Jdelorim | Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/joshua-delorimier/

Developer Website: https://www.joshuadelorimier.com/
New Media Art Website: https://www.trashtrashvisuals.com/

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer specializing in M.E.R.N. stack applications. Proficient in using current Web Development technologies. As a recent graduate of the University of Pennsylvania LPS Coding Boot Camp, the completion of the rigorous school program proves the ability to meet deadlines as well as strong ability to learn new technologies on the fly. For years has been applying computer science knowledge to make interactive art and developing game prototypes. Continues to be an accomplished real time media designer and video jockey. Has performed and presented artwork with some of the worlds top musical acts and DJ's. In the last three years has been invited to lecture at NYU Tisch School of the Arts on the subject of creating real time visuals with code. As a new graduate of UPenn's LPS Coding Boot Camp, I am looking forward to applying my new skills to web development projects.

Skills

Programming Languages: JavaScript, CSS, HTML, C#(Unity3d), Java(Processing)

 $\textbf{Frameworks}: \ React. js, \ Node. js, \ Handlebars. js, \ Express. js, \ jQuery, \ Materalize,$

Bootstrap, Processing, P5.js, Three.js

Databases: MongoDB, MySQL

Tools & Technologies: Git, Unity 3D, Quartz Composer, Adobe Photoshop, After

Effect, and Premiere, Cinema 4D, VDMX5

Code Samples & Projects

Digital Arts Scraper

Github: https://github.com/Jdelorim/DigitalArtsScraper

Deployed Project Site: https://digitalartsscraper.herokuapp.com/

A Full Stack application that scapes articles from Digital Arts Magazine. The user can save favorite articles as well as comment and delete them. Technologies used on this project: Node.js, Express, MongoDB, jQuery, Handlebars.js, JavaScript, HTML, CSS.

Memory Game

Github: https://github.com/Jdelorim/memorygame

Deployed Project Site: https://jdelorim.github.io/memorygame/

A Front End React.js web application that is a memory game. Click on each character without repeating each time you pick one the cards reshuffle. Technologies used on this project: React.js, CSS, HTML, JavaScript(ES6 features).

GenBots VR Demo

Github: https://github.com/Jdelorim/GoogleCardboardGameDemo

A one level prototype of upcoming oculus go virtual reality game GenBots VR. Technologies and tools used on this project: Unity 3d, Cinema 4D, Adobe Photoshop, C#.

Education

- Penn Coding Boot Camp (certificate) Full-Stack Web Development University of Pennsylvania 2018
 A rigorous 24 week program to build dynamic end to end web applications.
- Video Symphony (certificate) Motion Graphics/Film editing Burbank, CA 2006 - 2007 A year program to learn and master film editing and post production in the film industry.
- Wilmington University BS Motion Graphics and Design Wilmington, DE 2001 - 2005 Earned a Bachelor of Applied Science degree in Multimedia and Design.

Experience

D24K PRODUCTIONS, STAGE PRODUCTION/VISUAL DESIGNER - CONTRACT PHILADELPHIA, PA 2016 - 2018

- Long hour contracts with strict deadlines to complete complicated coordinated tasks.
- Designed real time music visualizers for production events.

BRDG STUDIOS, STAGE PRODUCTION - CONTRACT PHILADELPHIA, PA 2017 - 2018

• Worked in the warehouse helping on projects with BlinkVR, Kenneth Cole, and Lockheed Martin.

VISUAL INFINITY, NEW MEDIA DESIGNER – CONTRACT PHILADELPHIA, PA 2015 - 2019

- Re Edited Music Videos to live timecode for Simple Creatures tour(2019).
- Designed Animations for 5th Harmony Tour(2016).
- Performed and created Realtime interactive visuals at Camp Bisco Music Festival (2015-2017).
- Performed and created real-time interactive visuals at Moonrise Music Festival (2015).

M&M PARKING - TICKET MANAGER – CONTRACT PHILADELPHIA, PA 2013 - 2015

• Manager of ticketing operations for Coachella Music Festival (2013 - 2015).

ALICE IN ARMS – FILM EDITOR - CONTRACT LOS ANGELES, CA 2008 - 2009

• Lead film editor for the film "Dark Legacy"

COSMIC KAT PRODUCTIONS – FILM EDITOR - CONTRACT LOS ANGELES, CA 2008 - 2011

• Lead film editor for the films "Stand Up: Face the Fear", "I Witness News", "L.A. Sales".